let's explore cargo the rust package manager
the first use of cargo is to create new projects
if I run cargo new followed by a name of the project
let's go our project example
it will create a new project in my current directory
so now I can go to the example folder
in here I'll find my brand new rust project
and it will also initialize a
new git repository for me
there are
a couple of options that we can pass to cargo new
to explore them we can
type cargo new dush dush help
and this will list
the options that are valid for this command
for example we can specify
a different version control system other than git
or we can tell cargo to create a new
library application instead of an executable one
now let's open our new project in visuals to do code
so to do that I'll just
type code and current erectory
this will open up a new window
let me just move this to another workspace
alright great
at the route of every rust project there is a
cargo dot tomo file
in this file
we can specify the dependencies for our project
a metadata for the project and some compiler settings
in the rust world
packages are called crates
and in the dependency section here
we can list the crates that our project will need
the central registry for crates is the crates
or your website
that we can find here
and on the main page
we see a list of the most downloaded crates
so let's go and look at the most downloaded crate
which is the run crate
if we want to use this in our package
we just have to copy this line at the top
and put it in our cargo tomo file
so we just come here and under dependence is
we paste the
create name followed by the version that we would like
we can specify also just a part of the version
and it will still work
notice that when I
based at the new dependency I got this dumb up here
and it also shows me
all of the possible versions of this crate
this is a very nice feature that is provided by a
separate extension called crates
so if we look for crates we find this extension and
if you install it
you will get this nice feature
every time you are in your cargo tomo file
okay now let's see how we can build our project
if we head back to the terminal
all we have to do is type cargo build
and it will go ahead
look at the dependencies of our project
pull them and their dependencies
compile everything
link everything together and output a binary
it doesn't get much easier than that
and if we want to run our project we can use cargo run
so it will again build the project
but after it compiles and links everything
it will go ahead and run the binary
we see that for all new rust projects
we just
get a hello world printed from the main function
but this is not all that cargo can do
we can also use cargo to install
rust binaries that can be used system wide
later in this course
we will be using a 2 called cargo expand
if we come back to
crease dotayo and look for cargo expand
it pops up at the top
if we click to it
we see that it has an installation guide
and it tells us to run cargo in style cargo expand
let's go ahead and install it
so we just paste cargo in style cargo expand
and we run that
it will take a while because
cargo expand has a lot of dependencies
and after a quick fast forward
I have cargo expand installed on my system
right now
it doesn't really matter what cargo expand does
we will be using it in future videos
so now we can try and use it
so if we run cargo with the expand command
oh we get an error
it tells me thata 2 chain for the nightly x8664
Linux is not installed so what does that mean
rest is released
through 3
different channels with different levels of stability
there is stable which is the one you get by default
it is the currently supported version
and as the name suggests
it is the stable release of the language
that is meant to be used in production
then there is bitter
bitter is the candidate for the next stable version
and lastly there is nightly
nightly is the head of the master branch
where most of the development takes place
so nightly is very cutting edge
but it can be quite unstable
because the cargo expand
command
is using some unstable features of the compiler
it requires the nightly 2 chain
we can manage the different
2 chains that we have using the rest up to
so if we say rest up to chain list
we get the list of all the 2 chains
currently I only have stable installed
luckily the error that I got up here was kind
enough to tell me
exactly what 2 chain I need
so all I have to do is call rostop
2 chain
install and past the name of the 2 chain that I need
this will go ahead and install
cargo and rust sea and everything necessary
for the nightly rest 2 chain
now if I run rest up to chain list
we see that I have 2 to chains
the stable and the nightly end
stable is the default one